Guide to the Edward H. and Lotta C. Hume Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Edward H. and Lotta C. Hume papers
1897-1990
MS 787
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.5
The papers document the career of Edward H. Hume, a physician and educator, whose major work was divided between China, where he founded the Hunan-Yale Medical College (1914) and New York, where he was trustee and director of the New York Post-Graduate Medical School and Hospital (1928-1933). His life-long interest in Chinese medical problems is shown in his correspondence with members of the Yale-in-China Association staff. His subject files document the history of the various institutions of the Yale Mission in China, as well as political events during his stay. The papers also include copies of Hume's published and unpublished writings, newspaper clippings, and photographs. Lotta C. Hume's training as a nurse was put to use in India and China where she lived with her husband (1903-1927). Manuscripts of two books and a number of articles which she wrote on her return to the United States are in the papers. Of special interest are her research materials on Chinese and Tibetan folk tales, collected for a book on that subject. Apart from a letter on the Changsha riots in 1910, her correspondence is largely devoted to family matters.
Hume, Edward H. (Edward Hicks), 1876-1957
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Yale-in China Association during the 1930s, Charlotte Hume Freeman and Joy Hume Falk in 1977, Charlotte Hume Freeman in 1990, and David N. Freeman in 1995.
Arrangement
Arranged in seven series and two additions: I. E. H. Hume: Correspondence. II. E. H. Hume: Subject Files. III. E. H. Hume: Miscellany. IV. E. H. Hume: Writings V. L. C. Hume: Correspondence. VI. L.C. Hume: Writings. VII. L. C. Hume: Miscellany.
Scope and Contents
The Edward Hicks and Lotta Carswell Hume Papers are arranged in seven series.
Series I, EDWARD H. HUME: CORRESPONDENCE, contains letters between Hume and approximately eighty institutions and individuals, primarily members of the Yale-in-China Association staff. Correspondents of note include: Beach, Harlan Page, 1905-1919; Bevis, Palmer, 1924-1930; Dayton, Arthur Bliss, 1925-1932; Hutchins, Francis S., 1930-1937; Leavens, Dickson H., 1919-1927; Reed, Edward B., 1903-1909; Sallmon, William H., 1909-1914; Vreeland, Harold H., Jr., 1921-1924; Wilder, Amos, 1914-1919; Williams, F. Wells, 1911-1924; and Yen, F. C., 1924-1937.
Subjects discussed include the early organizational and building plans for the Yale Mission in Changsha; Hume's efforts to establish a first-rate medical school and hospital; political conditions in Changsha and Hunan; the attitude of Chinese students towards western education and culture; and routine business and administrative matters.
Series II, EDWARD H. HUME: SUBJECT FILES, contains approximately twelve reference files, primarily relating to the formulation of plans and policies for the Yale Mission. Also included are materials on anti-foreign disturbances in China during the 1920s, student strikes at Yali in 1925, and Hume's notes on the history of Yale-in-China and Hsiang-Ya Medical College.
Series III, EDWARD H. HUME: MISCELLANY, contains address books; financial records; photographs of Hume family members and Yale-in-China staff; biographical clippings on Hume; and miscellaneous Yale-in-China memorabilia.
Series IV, EDWARD H. HUME: WRITINGS, contains copies of Hume's published and unpublished writings. The materials are organized in five sections according to form: Articles and Professional Papers, Poems, Book Reviews, Memorials to Friends and Colleagues, and Research Notes.
Subjects include Chinese history, culture, politics, medicine, and education.
Series V, LOTTA C. HUME: CORRESPONDENCE, is divided into two sections:General Correspondence and Correspondence with Charlotte Hume and Norman Freeman.General Correspondence contains letters between Lotta Hume and friends, primarily members of the Yale-in-China Association staff. A single letter from 1910 gives Lotta Hume's account of the Changsha riots of that year. The letters for the years 1933 to 1972 discuss family business and Edward H. Hume's death.Correspondence with Charlotte Hume and Norman Freeman contains letters exchanged between Lotta Hume and her daughter and son-in-law between 1930-1972. Subjects discussed include family business, Lotta Hume's writings, and Edward H. Hume's activities.
Series VI, LOTTA C. HUME: WRITINGS, contains copies of stories and folktales written and transcribed by Mrs. Hume, as well as a typescript copy of Drama at the Doctor's Gate, an account of the Humes' life in China. Also included are research materials, notes, and copies of folktales collected by Lotta Hume during the course of her work on Favorite Children's Stories from China and Tibet..
Series VII, LOTTA C. HUME: MISCELLANY, contains biographical data, notices of Lotta Hume's death, and financial records. For photographs of Lotta Hume, see Series III, EDWARD H. HUME: MISCELLANY.
Box 15 contains fourteen folders of correspondence (1919, 1931-1951) between Edward H. Hume and Lotta C. Hume.
The materials composing the Edward Hicks and Lotta Carswell Hume Papers were deposited in the Yale University Library by the Yale-in-China Association during the 1930s and by Charlotte Hume Freeman and Joy Hume Falk in 1977.
Biographical / Historical
Edward Hicks Hume, physician and educator, was born on May 13, 1876, in Ahmednagar, India, the son of Congregational missionaries Edward S. and Charlotte E. Hume. He received his B.A. from Yale University in 1897 and his M.D. from Johns Hopkins University in 1901. After post-graduate work at the University of Liverpool and a residency at Johns Hopkins, Hume was appointed acting assistant surgeon with the United States Public Health Service in Bombay, India, in 1903. Before leaving for India, he married Lotta Carswell of Baltimore.
In 1905 Hume accepted an appointment to the Yale Mission in Changsha, China, where he organized the Yale Mission hospital. He served as senior physician of the hospital from 1906 to 1923. In 1914 Hume founded Hsiang-Ya (Hunan-Yale) Medical College after reaching an agreement with the governor of Hunan to cooperate in sponsoring medical education in the form of a new hospital and medical school. He served as dean of the school and professor of medicine until 1927. From 1923 to 1927 he was President of the Colleges (academic and medical) of Yale-in-China. He also served the Yale-in-China Association in several other capacities, including President of the Association (1934-1936), Vice-President (1955-1957), and Trustee (1927-1954).
In 1927 Hume resigned his offices at Hsiang-Ya and returned to the United States, where he became director and executive vice-president of the New York Post-Graduate Medical School and Hospital. Under his leadership, the school and hospital became part of Columbia University. From 1934 to 1937 he conducted a survey of medical facilities for the Chinese National Health Administration and in 1938 performed a similar service in India. A founder of the Christian Medical Council for Overseas Work, Hume was secretary of the organization from 1938 to 1946.
Among the organizations and institutions which Hume served as a trustee were the Associated Boards for Christian Colleges in China, the American Council of the Institute of Pacific Relations, the Harvard-Yenching Institute, Russell Sage College, and Lingnan University. He was the author of The Chinese Way in Medicine (1940), Doctors East, Doctors West (1946), Doctors Courageous (1950), and Dauntless Adventurer (1952). Hume died on February 8, 1957, in Wallingford, Connecticut.
Biographical / Historical
Helen Charlotta Carswell Hume was born on October 3, 1876, in Baltimore, Maryland, the daughter of Lockhart Scott Carswell and C. Annie Buckley Carswell. Called Lotta by her parents, she dropped Helen from her name after her marriage. A graduate of the Peabody Conservatory of Music in Baltimore, she enrolled in a course at the Hartford Theological Seminary and in a probationary course in nursing at Johns Hopkins University after her engagement to Edward H. Hume in 1900.
Following her marriage in 1903, she accompanied her husband to Bombay, India, where he worked for the United States Public Health Service. In 1905 the Humes moved to Changsha in Hunan Province, China, where Edward Hume had been appointed to the Yale Mission staff. In China, Lotta Hume assisted her husband as a nurse and research assistant and later started the first Social Service League in Changsha. She returned to the United States with her husband when he resigned his Yale-in-China appointment in 1927.
Lotta C. Hume was the author of "Lockhart Scott Carswell, a Portrait" (1933); Drama at the Doctor's Gate (1961); Favorite Children's Stories from China and Tibet (1962); and the compiler of Songs Along the Way (1957) by her husband, Edward H. Hume. The Humes had five children: Theodore Carswell (1904-1943); Charlotte Elizabeth Hume Freeman (b. 1906); Margery (1909-1911); Edward Welch (1913-1915); and Kathrina Joy Hume Falk (b. 1917). Lotta Hume died on February 17, 1976, in La Jolla, California.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Americans -- China; Folk literature, Chinese; Medicine -- China; Medicine -- India; Missions -- China; Asia; Changsha Shi (China); China -- Education; China -- History; Missionaries; Nurses; Physicians; Beach, Harlan P. (Harlan Page), 1854-1933; Bevis, Palmer; Dayton, Arthur Bliss, 1889-; Freeman, Charlotte Elizabeth Hume, 1906-; Freeman, Norman; Hume, Edward H. (Edward Hicks), 1876-1957; Hume, Lotta Carswell, 1876-1976; Hutchins, Francis S. (Francis Stephenson), 1902-; Leavens, Dickson H.; Reed, Edward Bliss, 1872-1940; Sallmon, William H., 1866-1938; Vreeland, Harold H.; Wilder, Amos Parker, 1862-; Williams, Frederick Wells, 1857-1928; Hua zhong shi fan xue yuan; Human-Yale College of Medicine. Hsiang-Ya Hospital (Changsha, China); Yale University -- Officals and employees; Yale-China Association
- EDWARD H. HUME: CORRESPONDENCE, 1903-1957; Series I; 2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The correspondence of Edward H. Hume is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Letters of a particular correspondent are arranged chronologically.
  - A, 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Board, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Medical Association, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Angell, James Rowland, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arnold, Lauren
    - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - B, 1919-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baltimore Sun, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Beach, Harlan Page, 1905-1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bevis, Palmer
    - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1925 (Box 1, Folder 11-14)
    - 1926 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    - 1927 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Boone University, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Burton, E. D., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - C, 1922-1955 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Campbell, E. Fay, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - China Society of America, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cowdry, E. V., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Crawford, Albert S., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - D, 1919-1926 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Dayton, Arthur Bliss, 1925-1932 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Dowd, Rachel A.
    - 1923-1949 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - E, 1919-1944 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Eddy, D. Brewer
    - 1908-1910 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 1923 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - F, 1923-1949 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Falk, Joy Hume, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Farnam, Henry W., 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Foreign Missions Conference of North America, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Freeman, Charlotte Hume and Norman
    - 1930-1935 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Freeman, David, 1934-1938 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Fulton, Robert Brank, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - G, 1920-1925 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Gabriel, Ralph W., 1925 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Gage, Brownell, 1907-1910 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - H, 1922-1940 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Hadley, Arthur T., 1912 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Hail, William J., 1912-1931 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Harkness, Edward S., 1922-1946 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Harkness Medical Land Fund, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Harvey, Edwin D., 1913-1925 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Holden, Reuben A.
    - 1950 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Hutchins, Francis S.
    - 1930-1933 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - 1934 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - J, 1914-1923 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Jack, Carmen V., 1924 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - January, Derick A., 1924 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Jefferson Medical College, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - K, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Kelsey, Clarence H., 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Knott, C. W., 1922 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - L, 1923-1946 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Leavens, Dickson H., 1919-1927 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Lobenstine, Edwin C., 1908-1936 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Lovett, Sidney, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - M, 1922-1935 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Morland, J. Kenneth, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - N, 1919-1923 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - North China Union Language School, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - O, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - P, 1922-1949 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions, 1920-1924 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - R, 1922-1925 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Reed, Edward B.
    - 1903-1905 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - 1906-1909 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Rinden, Arthur O., 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Roots, Logan H., 1924-1936 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - S, 1920-1947 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Sallmon, William H.
    - 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - 1912-1914 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Sanders, Morris B., 1924 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Seabury, Warren B., 1906-1907 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Smith, Robert Ashton, 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps
    - 1903-1914 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - 1915-1932 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions, 1919-1924 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - T, 1922-1950 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Toronto, University of, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - United Evangelical Mission, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - V, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Vaill, George D., 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Vreeland, H. Harold, Jr.
    - 1921 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - 1921 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - 1922 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - 1923-1924 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - W, 1923-1956 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Warfield, Marguerite D., 1922 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Wei, Francis C. M., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Weigle, Luther A., 1921-1955 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Weigle, Richard D., 1933-1937 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Wesleyan Methodist Missionary Society, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Wheeler, W. Reginald, 1922-1949 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Wilder, Amos P., 1914-1919 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Williams, Arthur C., 1904-1906 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Williams, F. Wells
    - 1911-1924 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - 1925-1927 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Williams, James W., 1914-1919 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Y, 1923-1948 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Yale-in-China, New Haven Office, 1910-1935 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Yen, F. C., 1924-1934 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Young Men's Christian Association International Committee, 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Z, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1919-1950 (Box 5, Folder 118)
- EDWARD H. HUME: SUBJECT FILES, 1909-1935; Series II; 0.5; (1 box)
  The subject files are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Anti-foreign disturbances in China: clippings and correspondence, 1920s (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Hsiang-Ya school song, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Hua Chung College: draft of constitution, undated (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Inauguration of Edward H. Hume as president of the Colleges of Yale-in-China: clippings and memoranda, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Medical reports, 1913-1925 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1916-1924 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Miscellaneous research notes, 1920-1924 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Plans and policy of the Yale Mission: memoranda, 1906-1924 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Memoranda
    - 1925 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - Reports of President Hume to the trustees, 1924-1935 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Scheme for a hospital in Changsha by E.H. Hume: (architect's drawing), undated (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Student strike at Yali: correspondence and memoranda, 1925 (Box 6)
  - Yale-in-China historical notes, 1909-1920 (Box 6, Folder 130)
- EDWARD H. HUME: MISCELLANY, 1907-1970; Series III; 1 linear feet (3 boxes)
  The materials in EDWARD H. RUNE: MISCELLANY are grouped together according to form.
  - Address book and addresses, undated (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - Biographical sketch and curriculum vitae, undated (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - Clippings re: E.H. Hume
    - 1907-1946 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - 1952-1961 (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - Clippings re: E.H. Hume's memorial service, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - Clippings re: publications by E.H. Hume, 1946-1952 (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 137-138)
  - Edward Hicks Hume Memorial Lectureship: memoranda
    - 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - 1960-1970 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Financial records, 1907-1926 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - Honorary degrees: clippings and programs, 1912-1925 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Hume family genealogical data, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - Hume, Robert A., fiftieth anniversary of service in India: testimonial pamphlet, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - Hume, Theodore Carswell, "Prayers and Meditations of Theodore C. Hume" (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Hume, Theodore Carswell, "Uncharted Voyage" by Ruth Seabury: memorial pamphlet and clippings, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Inventory of Hume materials in the Missionary Research Library, 1928-1957 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Memorabilia
    - Notebook of trips, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Chinese script (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Passports, 1918-1946 (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - Programs
      - 1909-1920 (Box 8, Folder 151)
      - 1938-1969 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - Yale College Class of 1897 fiftieth anniversary, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Fiftieth wedding anniversary, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - Photographs
    - Changsha (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - Family (Box 8, Folder 156)
    - Yale-in-China staff (Box 8, Folder 157-158)
    - Portraits of E. H. Hume (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - Portraits of Yale-in-China staff members (Box 9, Folder 160)
    - Negatives (Box 9, Folder 161-162)
- EDWARD H. HUME: WRITINGS, 1907-1956, undated; Series IV; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  The materials in EDWARD H. HUME: WRITINGS are arranged in five sections according to form: Articles and Professional Papers, Poems, Book Reviews, Memorials to Friends and Colleagues, and Research Notes. Within each section materials are arranged alphabetically. Because most of the items in this series are undated typescripts, few dates appear in the folder listing.
  - Bibliographies of addresses and articles by E. H. Hume (Box 10, Folder 163-164)
  - Articles and Professional Papers
    - "Achieving of Freedom in Human Life" (Box 10, Folder 165)
    - "All Night! All Day! Every Day!" (Box 10, Folder 166)
    - "American Contributions to Medical Education in China and India" (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - "An American Doctor Fights Cholera" (Box 10, Folder 168)
    - "Asia Speaks to the West" (Box 10, Folder 169)
    - Building Highways with Bandits and Witch Doctors -- Wastebaskets and Ricebaskets (Box 10, Folder 170)
    - "Building Medical Highways in the Desert" (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - "Bolshevik Influence Now Failing in China" (Box 10, Folder 172)
    - "China after the Shanghai Riots" (Box 10, Folder 173)
    - "China's Health Program Today and the Program of United China Relief" (Box 10, Folder 174)
    - "China's Nationalism and Foreign Relations" (Box 10, Folder 175)
    - "China's Record of Inventiveness" (Box 10, Folder 176)
    - "China's Tomorrow in Health and Education… is Today" (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - "Chinese Medicine and Modern Science" (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - "Chinese Pharmacy and Medicine" (Box 10, Folder 179)
    - "Christian Doctors at Work in War-Time" (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - "Christian Hospitals of China Face a New Century" (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - "The Christian Medical Enterprise Throughout the World As Affected by the War" (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - "Christian Medicine in China Tomorrow" (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - "Christian Ministry of Health and Healing Overseas" (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - "Christian Missions and Social Change" (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - "Christian Missions in China - Their Present and Future" (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - "Church and the Road to Health" (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - "Colleges of Yale-in-China" (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - "Concerning the Nation's Health" (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - "Conflict in China" (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - "Continuing Education of the Practitioner" (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - "Contours of Tomorrow's World" (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - "Contributions of Chinese Medicine" (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - "Contributions of David Livingstone As a Medical Scientist" (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - "Crisis in Eastern Asia" (Box 10, Folder 189)
    - "Crisis in Manchuria of Importance from Economic Side…" (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - "The Death of Marshal Chang of Manchuria" (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - "Deeper Wells" (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - "Doctor K. C. Wong" (Box 10, Folder 192)
    - "Eight-year Old Republics" (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - "Evacuate the Women and Children" (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - "Experiments on the Detection of B. Typhosus in Infected Material" (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - "Fight Against Leprosy, An Ancient Legend" (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - "First Medical Graduation in English-Taught Medical College in Central China" (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - "General Wu Pei-fu, China's Enigma" (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - "General Wu Pei-fu's Opportunity" (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - "General Wu Pei-fu's Victory - and After?" (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - "Great National Consciousness Beginning to Go into Every Nook and Cranny of Life in China" (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - "Health Beyond the Horizon" (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - "Herbs and Medicine in Ancient China" (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - "His Star in the West" (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - "How Doctor Wilbur's Successor Arrived" (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - "How Much of a Menace is Communism in China?" (Box 10, Folder 198)
    - "Hunan, Free from Rumors of War…" (Box 10, Folder 198)
    - "I Am Debtor" (Box 10, Folder 199)
    - "Ideas Cannot Be Bombed!" (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - "International Relationships of American Colleges in the East" (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - "Interpreting the Chinese Situation" (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - "Intrigues Endanger the Chinese Republic" (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - "Japan on the Crown Prince's Wedding Day" (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - "Keeping Doctors Up-to-Date" (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - "Launching of the Yale Mission to China" (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - "May Memories in China" (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - "Medical Education and the Christian Enterprise in China" (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - "Medical Education in China, prior to A.D. 1600" (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - "Medical Education in China: A Survey and Forecast" (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - "Medical Social Service from the Viewpoint of the Hospital Director" (abstract) (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - "Medical Work in Hunan Province" (Box 10, Folder 202)